The keynote really got you'll just up...
...better still not great or the keynote either just exhausted with all
the cool stuff that we announced and...you how many people have been
the build before static curiosity
okay pretty good repeat audience how many people have written application fragile before.
How many people are writing applications res right now...part of your job?
Ok, target audience that's good to see welcome to
lessen building applications rather lessons from scale my name is...image
...ceo for measure and what I'm going to share with you
the next sixty-minutes are some?
Tips on how to...design and application not just roger but just for cloud in
general of course I'll be focusing on address specific features rather than using other clouds but there's a number of
lessens a number of best practices that you're probably already familiar with that I'm not going to bore you
with like automation is great for cloud development and reproducibility
...great for...them...scaling out we all know that we can't scale-up anymore it's time to
scale out we've got at...are systems and production it's not good enough to
tasked in our own environments because what the world throws atis is something that we can't
simulate especially in the type site the application lifecycle.
That we've got today a agile development pushing things to the cloud.
Deploy early deploy often
this means small incremental updates rather than big monolithic updates every now and
then and that is great for helping you understand where there's a problem.
Exactly what it is rather than trying to finish it out of
a whole massive bunch of features and changes that have gone
into deployment but there's lots of other rules and that's what I'm going to spend the next sixty-minutes showing
you with real-world examples these are all actual stories from
as your customers they're all from the customer
advisory team this cat it's called the cat team and this is a team that is part of adder
it's sits in the engineering team but it's really are interface
with customers if you remember the movie office space they're the guys that
sit between engineering customers and actually they do a really good
...server really get purpose in this case which is to work with strategic customers
and interesting projects.
To understand how they're using our
product and how we can make it easier for them to user product in a couple different ways by providing
architectural guidance like I'm going to be doing here but also coming back to the engineering team and saying hey when they
try to use this service with this other one okay so that was
probably msit doing weird things on my system there trying to use this component with
other component that the there's a big impedance
...and engineering you guys need to go ad these features and make these connections more seamless?
The names of the customers on a
...except for one case that's a public customer that's.
Actually said it's ok to talk about their name as we go through this but.
I'm not going to spend time showing you the details of the names I will talk about the scenarios and I'll
talk about the actual applications that...developed and the
usage but if you've got a case that you come across yourself and
you're willing to share your name that be great because everybody likes to see who the real people are behind these kinds of stories I
want to say that this...been possible without the catching they.
Provided a tremendous amount of supporting collecting this kinds of cases in working with me
...digest them into the nuggets that would be interesting for an audience like this and they
also helped me produce some demonstrations that will show you with synthetic kind
of representations of the kind of not best practice performance that we saw from these
customers compared to what you get when you follow best practices so I'll be showing some
live demonstrations of that as well as we
go through here so let's get started this first cases a moving streaming company
that's a pretty big-name although not in the united states
...streaming company in europe and they started out as a
startup but five years ago for five years ago and they were one of the first kind
of interesting startups that showed up on...and we worked closely with them to make them successful
...the became successful enough that about a year-ago they were acquired by one of the largest
depart a retail store chains in the world a company called
...and this company right here is called
black box which does movie streaming...based out of the uk.
So, let's talk a little bit about this case they wanted they started up of course...in the
...so they went full paths and when you go full paths and measure today?
...means web roles worker roles asher database and
...storage and the
struct the architecture that they came up with is that viewers would come to the web role.
They had w staff protocol between the web role in the work role how many people have used
...windows communication foundation how many people like wpf.
Okay, everybody's entitled to their opinion.
So, they were using...promoting over tcp
...the web and worker role and they built a custom cash inside the work
...the cache the movie metadata so when a custom would come and say I want to
check-up the movies they would know exactly where to go in as your blob storage
...get the appropriate movie
and start streaming all that metadata was stored in the database so if there was a
cash mass than the metadata would be loaded from the database a pretty simple.
Architecture now the of course designing for cloud you need to
...for failures and one of the failures that they had designed for
whiz what happens if the cash query.
Times out what if it takes too long to query the cash from that front-end well in that
case they would go right to the database from the...if it took more than two seconds.
So, let's see what happened.
Or what kind of problems that kind of architecture produces
the issue is that there's kind of plan failures as well as unplanned failures in
...and one of the kinds of plan failures is if all...one of those worker
roles is getting recycled and now you've got load balance or
timeout you're moving between one work
...and that is going down for an update and another one that's healthy and that starts to
cause the front-ends that...talking to that work role in the cache there to start going directly
the database and what they found is as they started up and they were doing some
loads testing and production with real customers is that when
...activity when they were updating their roles or their host
...was being up against what is being updated that they would end up
making the database fall over and customers would start stop?
Having being able to query the movie information so the solution for this was
pretty straightforward exactly what you would think they added a cash to the front-ends.
And, that buffered against this kind of back-end
...so pretty straightforward case but again one of the things I want
to emphasize here is that these are real customers these are real
architects like you that are really making relapse they've
got the point where the apps are up and running and then they run into problems and at this point.
They're sitting here saying what is the
problem how do I make the performance of this thing better how do I work around this and that's when they
...so these are want cases where it looks obvious
in retrospect...all of these are going to look obvious and retrospect and that's really the
way architecture works out when you start with about architecture and you don't understand...
architecture and then you figure out why it's bad it's like obvious and so.
Again, you're looking here and I
think come to the end of this talk and say okay I didn't really learn anything but I hope you do
learned something here because even just looking at a case like this is
going to make you think as you go through your architecture design I remember that problem that
link box ran into where they didn't have caches to buffer against the case...worker roles
...in the middle of being updated so I need to think about that particular scenario ahead of time
rather than get the architecture up and running and then run into this in production this next case
is customer that does election tracking and...hired by the state governments to
track elections this was back in twenty twelve this particular
case the customer created a service to track and report the live tally a
...of the elections at the time across the
local state and the national level and this was being deployed for a
very large united states state.
And, there was...elections and that year one is the september primaries and they serve that
one just fine but
...the national action came up they were concerned about whether
their architecture would survive the load and of course serving the state election results to the
...with a huge responsibility for them because voters are looking what's
going on wanting to understand if their candidates are winning and if that election
site went down that election results site went down then everybody's kind of in
the dark the presses in the dark as well so
they wanted to make sure that they absolutely had everything button down for this national election.
Question was...architecture...that's when they called
...team just to make sure that it would really scale so the cat team comes in
and here's the architecture that they found so they've got a whole bunch of precincts that are collection collecting revolts
...locally and those precincts are uploading...voting results to
asher blobs and they're partitions so that a number of precincts or uploading
...blob blobs in different storage accounts and then you've got worker
...sucking from the blobs and sticking the aggregated results into adrg database.
...come in from the front through
a load balance or they hit a web role and the web role is then
querying the database for the results to show them what the results are that they're interested in so they're
going and saying hey who's winning in my county, for example.
They also in this is kind of not material to this particular lesson but should to show you
what customer like this that is really concerned about being
resilient through a major event like this and actually just anybody that's got
emission critical application how you might design your application for disaster
recovery is that they deployed to versions to instances of that same architecture
...self-centered us and want
to north-central us exactly the same deployments that only differences they...they had
...warm fail over system here where the worker role in the
primary which was started out as south-central us would not only dump to the local database
ritz deployment but also...the aggregated results into the database across the
country into north-central us so if there was a problem they would just simply fail over
and they used after measure traffic manager do dns fail over.
So, if measure traffic manager was having trouble talking
to south-central us it would automatically fail over dns to north-central us the results would still
would be there and voter results would pick up where they left off.
Each web request in this architecture as the catching dug in to the code results
intense equal queries so it's go get the customer go get the
county go get the voter information go get the county go get the results
for whatever precinct get the results for the national level
...a whole bunch of different queries are involved in reporting the results to
the user so the load estimates for the november election that they came up with
...an average of.
Ten million.
Expected page views on average with a
...in one-hour of six millionso,
ten million over the for our time that people would start to look at the results of
...of six million and just multiplying out the number of database requested see
they came up with about sixteen thousand seventeen thousand date queries
per database that they had configure at the peak the problem is that they
...database that they were using scales only five thousand connections and a
hundred eighty concurrent requests with a hundred eighty a hundred requests per second.
A little bit lower than what
...projection set so they said okay so we've got we do have a problem with this architecture
we need to drastically change it to be able to handle this kind of...that we're going to see the november election.
So, the solution again this is another case of caching is let's prakash between the
front-end and the database and make sure that cash can deliver forty thousand
request for instance which is how many request they could get off of a web role.
Talking to a worker role where the worker role is doing local caching.
So, this at the time was asher cash now they be using...cash as...cash to do
this kind of caching between the web role in the database so now the voters are
talking to these caches that are then faltering and from the database when necessary.
They skin scale it out each one of these worker...and you can see this is the exact
apology for worker roles times forty thousand requested each can
handle second hundred sixty thousand requests so how this do that's architecture
they came up with looked like on paper would meet the election results the
cat team so this is the actual...the of the traffic's
...saw on election night you can
see that for some reason my animations got lost but you can see...that at eight o'clock.
That was the peak voting time they hit forty five thousand concurrent requests.
Swf significantly lower than a hundred sixty thousand that
they budgeted for plenty ahead room so they planned a core okay, but,
when you go back and look at what how it performed with the original architecture you can
see the over the course of that election night how many request
they would not have been able to serve without original architecture
in the worst-case five hundred-thousand requests would not have been served that's those negatives
and parentheses and how did it really do with the cash
...is what they saw everything and green this eight plus ten seconds
where the negative there that's estimated capacity that's that was estimate that's not what they really stop
it the results spoke for themselves they were able to handle the load completely so this these
were the analysis that they did before and after with the
cash so cashing a great?
Way to...performance and let's just show you an example of caching
and I'll show you this example for that will demonstrate the our of caching as well as demonstrates
...other capabilities that you can take advantage of when you're working on applications.
Imagine what I've got here...application side-by-side.
Get the so I can.
You can see that this is a bunch of database query
...bunch of queries get customer get employee so the front-ends for this particular application for each
request comes in from a client is going to perform a number of these different queries like getting a
custom id getting employee id and.
This is the...function on the non cash side so this is just a
straightforward query for into the database to get
the customer information on this right side we've got a little bit of a different architecture.
...can't see what I'm doing when I zoom like that.
Let me show you here this is get
customer right here and you can see that we've got
...highlight this code snippet so this is cashed customer
repository and here we try to get the result from the cash before.
If they can only...cash is...does it go to the database
...database hit is then going to result in that query getting cashed
in the database so this is the side-by-side comparison we're going to perform
and what I'm going to do for you is exercise?
This live.
I've got another vm here.
And, this vm.
Has load generator configured it and let me show you how easy it
is to configure...generator in visual studio so I'm going
to go to?
This no cash example I'm going to select...
Select load test and then there's a little wizard
...you through the low test and you can see here there's a number of different options
use recorded thing times use normal distribution on recorded things times do
not use recorded thing times we're just going to let the normal distribution here.
There's constant load you can also have step loads if you want to...load ramping up and see
the behavior of that or constant load you can base the result the test makes modeled on total number
...on the number of virtual users.
So, bunch of different options here and then.
You add one or more task to the...so I'm going to add one here.
And, that's gives you an idea of I pressed okay we would be just be
creating a new load test right there that would be able to run against the...I've already can rated a couple of
...tasks one to that will hit both the...on cashed load set up here.
And, that is right here and that can cash no cash case we're going to hit the
no cash apple application with is this scenario right
here attest mixed that shows us that we're going to do a bunch of those queries
for simulating the fact that for every user query when I hit every
one of these methods that's going to end up hitting the database.
And, one of the things I can show you here is if I say...on.
...here and select this
one of the other things that you can do.
Is you can see that the cashed get customer low test here is hitting
url so this is where we got the app running and the query
here is get customer id and then there's an idea here we're going to do?
Is an whatever he does configure a random?
Id so you specify in
this web test plug-in you can specify how you want.
Values to get plugged into the url.
So, that id,
for example, we wanted to be a random aidid selected from our customer database
...customer database...start eleven thousand go
up to eleven thousand three hundred seventy six that's the number of ideas that we populate in the database some
...have the load tasked whenever it generates a query.
Fill in that id with a random value from that range.
And, that's how easy it is to general a load test.
The other thing you can do...you can have.
You can have visual studio generate the low test or you can...have the local machine generate the
...test now I'm going to have the local machine generate the load test.
And, to do that and, this is basically hit run so this is the cash side over here this is the
cash side over here we're going to fire up this low test.
Low test on both sides and in a second here graph is going to pop open.
Haven't seen this...before?
Let's see if that ...running makes that go away.
You know, retry is another lesson from the...and there we go networks.
So,...know what just happened but whatever it is we got it working.
Now...running I want to show you something really quick and how easy it is to have
a visual studio generate these loads here you can see that
when I have the load when I configured...test
...might local load test configuration says run the load locally so
this rd svm this one vm hitting both and on
...and cashed websites with low generated here but you can also easily
configured to have visual studio generate the load test?
And, that's going to become interesting here as we look at the output of this
date result.
We've got the to loads firing up here and the results which shows us pages per
second.
And, the response time as wellboth of the on the left side the non
...case and...case on the right side.
They kind of dull looked at dissimilar until you look at the scales.
Which is something that you gotta watch out for these load test results because the scale here in
pages per second the range from the top to the...to the bottom as a thousand and over
here the pages per second the top range from the top-to-bottom as a hundred?
So, in that is this green-line here so we're hitting close to forty thousand
requests per second over here on this side were hiding
around ten you can see the average is ten so this
is quite a dramatic difference of throughput that we're getting between the
...in on...case and you can see that the throughput continues to go up as a...gets populated.
On each of those database...
So, that's a look at.
And, the behavior of cashed in on cashed in front of a
database kind of obvious and...again this is one of those things that on local
small-scale application you don't typically need to worry about putting a
...from the database the databases a high-performance database you
can scale it up to meet your needs and hit as hard as you can now when you're in
a clouding you're talking to paths database you get a certain amount of throughput your scaling out typically
...like in a case like this to a larger architecture then you might have design for on
...so this is where you start to need to worry about caches this next case is a
customer that was basically lipton...customer they...application architecture that they
wanted to move the klout and they said well we're moving into the cloud let's modernizing.
And, this company.
It's a company that makes plans for buildings
...basically...civil engineering spatial infrastructure they wanted
this leverage all the coolest technology dot net sequel password possible and they were
shooting for the performance of their existing performance a common request and requirement when you're moving
...cloud is I want at least as good performances and getting on cram.
So, here's where they started moving...dot net.
Code to a web role move the application logic
to worker role move sequel to add your database or sorry and I as
sql memory so this is a case where they had application compatibility requirements on sequel
...met at the time by advert database pushing them into this.
Now what they did they got this.
Scale results were disappointing.
On prim thirty thousand thirty three thousand counts for.
Batch test run total counts on as
...ten thousand on interactive
workload hundred fourteen thousand was the throughput forty thousand what is what they got
a manager so drastic difference in performance that's when
they called in measure cat and the on...architecture had a combined web
and app server and this inner role communication that they...when
...the cloud was causing a lot of round-trip...between the web role in the worker role.
So, they collapsed the web and worker role at that point in time.
And, the storage...wasn't really optimized for
...usage so when what they done it was configure storage
bases...server two thousand twelve rtwo...use...striking the default
column that storage places gives you and they put both of the tempt the
database hd and the tempt...
Phd on the same storage space volume and that resulted in this...throughput
that they saw that they got of eighteen hundred...megabytes per second as.
Your cat came and said there's a better way to scale this out so let's put some more
disks under this and let's get the column count
raised on storage spaces and let's put those separate db that separate
On separate
...on the same...combine them into one...one volume.
And, what they got here was fifty three hundred
apps and three hundred megabytes per second so drastic improvement just by re architect
...the storage underneath the ins
disks to better take advantage of the performance characteristics of
...disks up in adder?
So, here's the performance test results that they saw at this
point this is on the far-left what they saw on cram in the middle
is what they saw and that first architecture with the throughput that I showed you
in on the right is what they got with this revised architecture collapsing the web
and worker role making the storage space stripes whiter and putting those to
...those
...databases on this to...on the same volume or to databases on the same volume and
they got this level...performance that actually slightly exceeded what they saw on prom so
a modern application now with the exception of really the iso role they had web
role basically in the front...so they were taking advantage of
...butperformance on a lipton shift application moving the cloud that
...with this on...
Is a company?
That it uses a high a hybrid architecture or
hybrid paths architecture to pulled data from lots of client
endpoints mobile devices as well as web
browsers click activity from users and then feeds that into
analytics system that does targeted ads for those particular users through
an at opt in app that those users put on their systems and...one of
leaders in that space.
And, the architecture works like this they've got local.
On prim sources that are pulling this data from devices around the
world.
Putting...files and uploading...menagerie blobs.
And, then they're importing that into asher database within ingestion worker role that's reading from the blogs
...shredding
the cthree files and sticking those into the database they also
needed a severing...trailing aggregate view for analytics so
that they could understand how they were doing in terms of responsiveness
...the users clicking on the target ads and for that they used html site
in cloud ml to analyze the previous seven days.
So, here's the challenge that they ran into when they started with this architecture the
sourced data hundred
csp files coming from the different sites that they had.
Roughly ten megabytes twelve hundred one-point-four gigabytes and size of each...file.
...average total ingest per day was around forty gigabytes.
So, they wrote this is a huge amount of data be ingesting up in adder into the database so they wrote a
custom et up process using sequel book copy
and the problem was that even with that the ingest.
Took thirty seven hours.
So, if you do the math here it kind of doesn't work out.
So, what did he...that the asher database is a scale architecture
not scale-up architecture so the first thing they did was move the database to
agile premium, premium skew of the database this-is before we
have the latest skews this-is about a year-and-a-half
ago and this is actually the golden rule right here
for getting great performance I'll just pay more money and go up to the next highest?
I'm just kidding but in some cases it is
the most efficient way to address the problem is just you might be at the...performance
of the offering and that's just not enough to cut the what your shooting
for so you might need to move up or consider moving up rather than trying to
work around the...performance you're going to get that lower tier and see if you can solve the problem in
other ways sometimes just throwing money at the problem's going to save in a...term.
They also paralyze that it upload by scaling up the worker role to...streams instead of just having one worker
...sucking...up so they partition those blobs...worker role another worker
roles are independently sucking data up from those blobs and then they also instead of talking things in
the database they create one table per day
in different what instead of stick everything into one table
and one database they created multiple databases one for each day so when they're
ingesting they just jump into that days database that...sorry table.
And, then they've got an aggregate or on top that is look that is pulling
and aggregating across the previous seven days so the next day comes over once they got the pipeline full of
seven days the next comes in they toss the
...all this day and then they aggregate a runs over the latest seven days to
get that aggregated view that they're going to do the html site machine learning on top of and the result is
that this optimized architecture the upload took less than three hours.
And, they were able to analyze all of that data and get their daily...
For those analytics that they needed.
So, the conclusion on this one paralyzing this is
kind of another example partitioning the problem
partitioning the database to partitioning...blah-blah-blah...with those worker roles
and then instead of just having a one giant table of data and then having to
go and delete roles that are older than seven days partition that also
...different tables because that's your problem is really day it's a
daily problem not a full arbitrary amount of time problem so you can optimize your
sequel for this kind of solution this next
cases car company it's a telematics car company.
That has services where they pull data from cars.
And, stick it and process...
and gives users information about the cars give dealers information about the cars and what they
want to do is create a solution on the agile cloud by leveraging underpass services?
So, to do this here's the architecture data admin web role and I'm
showing you the full architecture here there's pieces not involved with the direct promises to give an idea that these are real
architectures and the pieces that they make-up they've got a user services web role that's where users
can go get informations about their car they've got the cars themselves the cars are pumping
data into the cloud using service bus and you can see that there's a bunch of
worker...here that are processing that data so they've got a message processor worker role that
pull that's actually reading the data off of the service...notification work
role that's got rules-based on those messages that are
...that the message processor is sending it so,
for example, if the car...low oil maybe that's an alert and that's
a message that came in through the service plus q and then they've also got a
cash as well and sitting in front of a database
...dumping information about what the cars how the
...performing in its history of notifications so they did have a
cash but now let's talk about what they saw performance measurements showed that it was
far less than their target of ten thousand
requests per second that they wanted come from cars.
They...a few problems when the captain
came and they identified with this one is synchronous message processing
so those if you go back to this architecture that message processor.
Although scaled out each one of those worker roles with sitting and pulling one message off
the q processing it and then going back in getting the next one.
So, you've got the serial flow of messages going into the message processor the
fix for this one was to have asynchronous are batch
...so that multiple messages would be delivered in one shot through the
q to the worker role when data read from the service
...q we get a several messages rather than just one in one shot.
The second problem is that processing one by one that they were doing so yes you can batch it
...that...the round trips to the service...q but if you're going to go
process those messages serially you still have a bottleneck there.
So, the thanks for this concurrently process those messages,
messages come in a batch fire off processing for each one can concurrently
and asynchronous like.
And, this
the solutions these to fix that I showed you here also relatively obvious but a lot of people you service
plus without thinking about these kinds of challenges in these kind of bottlenecks you can create when you use it
in...straightforward manner here's a link to guidance on using
service bus effectively which includes things like using concurrency and using...
asynchronous processing like I've shown you here and I've got an example
of how this team dramatically impact processing.
To show you here.
By the way.
Take a look.
And, this is the serial worker role and this is.
Asynchronous worker role.
Sorry patchwork role is what I want here.
Now in this left side this is reading from the message but the service
...here one message processing
the message now this is a synthetic app so the amount of time that it's going to
take the process that messages actually coming in the message that the load generator sending it's a
low generative saying hey here's a message spend half a second processing
...second processing this message...
simulate that you're actually got real stuff to do on that back-end and then there's progress tracker that
...see how fast progress this makes churning through the messages that
...generators going to throw it on this right side...
The similar loop with one key difference.
Well, right here there's two one is that
we're firing off the.
Message the processing asynchronous lee and the second is that we configured the service
bus q to give up to fifty messages in each
shot so batch them up into fifty messages
each time that we go read from the service plus q now we gets fifty of the
q and fire them off the processing of them all off asynchronous
...so now we can have up to fifty being processed at once we're on the left side each one is
done serially one by one if we take a look at the load of our
I've already run this the...generator.
Results loaded.
Here's the synchronous load test and.
Usually asynchronous load test.
And, what we're looking at
is the performance and again the interesting thing?
Here to note is...that.
...to do that...
Trying to...get so I consuming for you.
Is that the?
Scales on these graphs are very different if we take a look at the average response time for the
serial case you can see that the average is about twenty seconds and that's because load
...load...saying it's picking random load somewhere between fifteen and twenty.
Average response time per second.
...sorry I'm showing...results that would help.
This is the
...this is the next test sorry about that I'm showing you her own test.
That helps getting my demos confused here.
What I wanted to show you?
Is I think this is other actually on the other vm?
Here we go here's the back here is this is actual live...
start not this the can...which is going to be the next...preview the next results for you.
But, this one is the service...batch versus...the load
task is going to generate a hundred messages give it to the one that's doing
say a serialized request and give it to the one that's doing is asynchronous request
...just press the button this is...the live production as
your service and this was just show us the results if it behaves for us.
So, something's going wrong with the...and try that again.
...serially one serial one seems to not be responding.
Let's write one more time this is...risk of doing live demos.
Is that the...sometimes...on you and punish you?
And, what...I guess maybe let's just pretend
ethereal one is going to take forever because it's so inefficient?
And, that's the lesson...don't do it serially.
...the actual results here would be that the
and normal perform behaviors that this one
tech actually that and take thirty five seconds or something that took like three seconds.
All right so that...really
funny is going on with this because that is like three seconds not thirty five seconds
and over here we should see about ten seconds or twelve seconds rather than three thirty
five seconds so something funny going on with that demo but.
You get the idea batching set of perform
things sequentially this next cases a company that makes thermostat for buildings.
They got tempt thermometers all over the place
...buildings not just one per building but obviously on dot lots of different places the
...the basement in the different rooms in the hallways and they report the temperature these
...smart thermostat to cloud service now the
...service is the point where building managers and
the built the building customers can interact with hvac systems in those buildings
...the building managers can look at the result of the thermostat the results coming from the
thermostat and understand...is the building operating efficiently...my paying too much money on cooling
and when the weather it's nice and cool outside maybe that template the
air-conditioning up too high and customers can go in there configure where they like the heating
cooling to be by looking at the building temperatures that are being reported by these thermometers
...this was a big product launch for...cloud service to do this at massive scale across other
buildings rather than kind of having the on premises deployments they had all over scattered all over the place
the initial product failed to reach their goals which was thirty five thousand connected thermostat?
Their target.
Was a hundred-thousand...stretch goals hundred-fifty thousand so that's when they brought in the
...team to help them with the architecture and here's architecture that they had
course they've got hvac systems and buildings with thermometers they've got a building router.
That is then collecting information's kind of a local gateway that's
aggregating is temperature results from the different devices in
the building and setting them up to a web role using synchronous http.
Not that that's a warning right there dumping it into a database and then.
Worker roles all over the web roles also processing the temperatures
...the other information coming from
...hvac systems and dumping alerts into asher
...which would then
email things alert notifications to the dealers and hra
...on prom smtp using on that prime smtp
...they also another web role which was the user interface
...customers in the building using a devices to go and look at the what's going on
...building change things and that was also could talking to the agile database to get
information one of the settings in the building what's the history the what's been going on
that building and then I mention that they also correlate this with the weather so
the users can understand the weather and also the hvac systems can respond to the weather ahead of time as well if it
knows that's going to...ninety degrees...by ten o'clock in the morning let's start to cranked...
or up at nine o'clock so that it can be still cool when the temperatures rising ahead of
time so that's a quick look at the architecture and here's the initial performance
low test results that you can see the read our successful request you can see that
we're getting up to about a thousand requests per second and then at the...that...an anomaly of the
...and then at the bottom you also see this low-grade blue line which
are http five hundreds anybody know...http five hundred...
...internal server error.
So, really not scaling well.
The biggest issue in this architecture was the one that I flag for-you which is the synchronous http handler on the
front-end talking to those clients systems so they change the catching
cayman hey let's change this so only the interactive
cruiser synchronous only the ones were customers are actually clearing or
what results and back need to be synchronous the ones where they're changing things
...ones where it's ingest of information those don't need to
...because nobody's waiting for anything at that point in time just drop it in
and go and...also doing single role updates...the database of easy fix to this
is to start doing batch multi role update to the database to minimize the number of round-trip
...and...also using a single low-end as
your database so the goal here's another example in this case
...little bit more cost optimized there's some tables that were hot some tables that
...like building information that's relatively cold the
...stuff you're dumping temperatures into well that's going to be a hot table because you're writing into it all the
time so move that to the premium database and leave the
...tables in the lower-cost database here to save some money
they were also preserving xml parameters in the database which caused a lot of extra processing on
the database queries so they converted those into table value parameters and then they were using a
single asher q and what they did was...switch to multi
...service plus q that's another example of guidance you'll find that page which is
...partition your service plus...again we're in a...world and
in partitioning will give you better parallelism and throughput?
And, this is the updated architecture now so hvac system here
you've got the key differences here are those lines the sink
...asic results the hvac systems.
Probe processing mostly asynchronous...mostly asynchronous
request except for the end-users which are getting synchronous http
request the synchronous reads are coming from the asher database you
can ad asynchronous rights going-to from up to the database from the worker
role which is also doing right leveling at the same time.
And, that is the key difference there that worker roll over there with the service
...between the web role in it which is kind of buffering the database.
And, also servings and immediately on the whether queries in the
email.
Pipeline.
So, let's see the results...the load test they ran after that you can see that
were scaling up now at the...above twenty-five and requests per second
...five or threes that you see there those are also just anomalies of the
...at so they were very happy with this kind of performance they were getting and they're able to hit...
the stretch goal that they'd set of a hundred-fifty thousand connected thermostat with the kind of performance
...seeing here after they started scale this out so
successful case now this is where I'm going to show you synchronous versus a synchronous.
Response and.
Okay,
yeah, okay, maybe the there we go so you can't say that I had a demo failure.
Here's the synchronous load test and.
Which you already kind of saw and here's the asynchronous low test and now here?
I go back to where I was talking about.
...me to show you the code I guess for the synchronous and asynchronous...tests.
So, here's the synchronous
controller and here's the asynchronous controller and.
...trying to...trying
...zoom it that I can't do that very well through this internet connection.
The key difference here is if you look it's fully synchronous, synchronous controller.
...user profile get your profile this is all done completely synchronous
...and over...right side you can see that we've got a...here with a
...await the paralyze all of these requests.
And, the results of this under load with
the synthetic load art as what you see here first of all
...performance you can see that we get a very constant level a performance in this is
a response time of two seconds so the response time which is the average here
...two seconds over here you can see that the response time is all
over the place and it's actually going up and you can see
the average through the whole run was about twenty seconds so once it started
to go up it's kept on going up and we had very flaky performance and
if you take a look at throughput you'll also see another very dramatic difference here's the throughput that
...load test was able to get again this range here on this graph
as a thousand operations never hear requests per second thousand so this is
equivalent scale
that you can see that this is able to achieve up here on the high into the graph.
Over around somewhere around nine hundred requests per second
and over here on the left side you can see that were only able to get around eighty
requests per second so ten-x the performance difference just based on
that little change of going from synchronous to asynchronous on that front
end which is one of the like I said that he highlight
problem of this architecture was...http response...which is completely synchronous.
So, this next one smart card application.
They do smart card
authentication for e-commerce they had a traditional so what
...web role cash role as...database...an example where they did have a
cache the problem was that the web role would randomly crash?
And, this case I just want this kind of just a general how to write a
web apps guidance it's not specific...but again
this interesting case because this company creating this...application.
Pretty serious company been business for a long-time doing
...stuff they go to the cloud they create a web role and then they run into this problem with web
roles randomly crashing.
And, they can't figure it out and they call the cat team.
So, these random crashes are hard to reproduce of course let's take a look at what the
cat team found.
This is the actual code that they had in their web role I'm just
kidding I didn't have this code...the web role.
So, this.
Big basically on button click from the website split up a new thread on each
one and the thread would go off and do things and the thread didn't have a global exception
...around it so exceptions...pop-up they wouldn't be handled
and now not only does that thread fault but the whole process faults
in this thing is running inside the same processes the this code the handler so the
of the web role crashes completely?
The other problem that they had was that if the back ends went down because this
synchronous processing on these different threads all the threads get start to get
piled up you're all busy doing stuff and every one of these request...a new thread.
And, that also can lead to exceptions because you can run out of memory and you also get
into resource starvation of the threads all start to wake up at the same time that you get cpu spikes now
the front-ends becomes completely unresponsive and then it has
another problem that I mentioned of the exception handler not being there so the resolution of this
one...they moved.
...worker logic to...and connected the web role asynchronous...through service
...q...in this actually this case...storage q to the...so
de-couple the front-ends in the back ends of course put in some resilience here on these kinds of faults.
This next cases a company that does contract management software.
So, kind of contract workflow software.
This is
their architecture front-end has a user interface has rest api on
...middle tier also has an api that the front-end...business logic some workflow
in it and then work role does batch processing on some of those workflows.
They've got storage for document where they're putting this contract files and they've
got metadata and reporting on the contract workflows that they sticking to...database.
They've got a lot of chatty api is so those api is between front-end the middle
...that's a chatty interface and they also have a chatty interface to
the database like we've seen before and some of these other examples.
And, also a couple of other issues...doing xml processing
in tc cool as they stick things into the database because they want things to be
in the database in xml format.
And, they're doing all tp queries on the database that
are also dumping those that...those results into so
few problems that they ran into this chatty database calls it a page load
at a contract load...tian reporting on the same database interfering with each other so
these are all tp queries which can be.
Long kind of long-running those don't have to be instantaneous
as people are doing these kinds of queries interfering with your more realtime.
Dumping of data into the database
...also generating the data at the metadata is xml on the database itself.
And, then they've also got a stored procedure that's also doing stream processing on those xml queries which
is also putting more load on the database as well as a whole bunch of problems so let's just avoid the database
where we can they move the...xml processing on to the middle tier.
They move the reporting to the geo replica so one of the things you can get with
...database you get this for just disaster resilience...they
...is you get copies of the data copy to a second instance
...another region.
And, you can redo reads from that so that's a great place to durell to
...it's a separate instance of the database...your.
Rights are going into the primary...reads are coming off the secondary not interfering with each other and
your basically making use of money that you're paying for that second database
...they change the single change to a single query where they code on the
front-end those rest api calls that consolidated some of those calls on the back-end
consolidated sequel curries into minimum number
of queries and what they saw was ten-x performance improvement and this is
the updated architecture search chunky ios on the front xml processing the middle
tier and reporting at the geo replica rather than the primary and I've got an
example here of load test on a synthetic
app that does exactly what we're just talking about?
So, if I go to.
Good the browser again.
I thought I had a code sample for this one.
Yeah, actually.
This is.
This is right here.
Tough to keep track of all these demos here we go so we've
got this busy database example and we've got the...
query in sql let me show you the sql query so this is a sql
query that's doing a whole bunch of xml which is actually not what you want at all.
For performance.
And, here's the controller for this which is simply doing a
basically sequel can one...command.
And, just waiting for it so very simple kind of controller.
Because all the work is being done in that sql query that we saw back here this complicated
Which is doing this?
If we take a look at the query on the one where the processing is done on the middle
tier here's the sql query it's a lot simpler to understand a lot
less resource intensive on sequel and if we took a look at the
controller...that work moved into the controller itself and you can see here in
building up the xml...going to be putting into that.
And, that's where we've got this low task here so this
is xml processing in the database layer this is hitting the left side example
and on the right side we've got hitting that right side example.
Ten queries.
Xml on the database versus xml in the middle tier
...of performance difference that you can see drastic improve
...a drastic difference with that simple code that you saw
it there created causes this kind of drastic
difference in fact in this customers case here's the example of the throughput
that they saw on the database so the load on the database here
on the busy one this is actually from this synthetic query that we just saw
but very similar to what this customer...like I mention ten-x performance improvement they saw eczema processing the
middle tier versus on the app...the load on the database
went from eighty seven percent down to thirty seven percent so lots more lots more head room for
lots more real work on that database rather than the stuff that they should've been doing somewhere else.
And, we got one last example here photo sharing application so companies doing.
Photo sharing and image processing in the cloud offering
customers unlimited storage the first release said fifty were limited fifty request per second their
target was seven thousand requests per second.
And, here's the problem.
This architecture right here everything in one web role very hey let's go to
...let's go to pass then they created all of these services inside the web role
with one database on the back-end for and they and they
also here's another key thing that they have got wrong is that for every one of these queries.
To these other services they were using a different http request are actually using http
in-between these things because they migrated from another architecture where these things
...using http.
So, just a horrible, horrible architecture that a real one that they called the cat team
in so the cat team we factored architecture...separate web...worker roles they changed
Builds...they change the asynchronous calls across the architecture
...they actually optimized for storage instead of taking all the pictures in the database they stuck them
some place else and this is now where
you see what's going on image processing goes to blob store.
You see the cash.
Being sir stored...durable cash being stored in table storage and then you see a cash in front of
adrg database and you also see that they're using reusing http
connections as they talk from these one service which now is in a separate web
role to these other web roles which have their own dedicated services
so big difference in architecture and let's go take a look.
...example.
Of that.
...visual studio and I'll show you the results of this as well.
New http request per control pretty straightforward you see http
client new client request per each request and on the right side.
Single-a single http request for client.
And, that's.
Demonstrated by this fact right here you can see there's one
http client that's just simply being reused on every one of these requests here and also we
see asynchronous processing so let's go take a look at the results for this.
Here's the throughput for.
Performance for the one where we're
creating a new request for every new http client request
...one and the one...seeing.
For bat asynchronous reuse of the same http request
a client sorry it should be client and you can see the average response time here.
Average is.
Around one-point-two seconds average response I'm here is point-two
seconds so six x difference in response time.
And, we'll see the same kind of benefits.
On throughput as well again if we're taking like a
requests per second you see the scale here is ten-x with the scale...over here one thousand
...here ten thousand scale over here.
And, the request per second goes up to about three thousand
in over here it's hovering around.
Six hundred so,
massive difference just from that simple code changes well so that brings me the conclusion the talk.
And, here the kind of lessons that I hope you took away from this
cash aggressively always worry about caches local caches, caches between your database caches
ogg between your web and worker role where you can asynchronous processing with
...where possible processing batches minimizing round trips between
your various tears partition your data and compute...take advantage of scale
architectures and then use the database for database work not for other work and take advantage
also in your database and other places where you can of those secondary that you've got which you can
also do processing from all of these cases are available right here at this get
have repository this whole project is so you can go look at these examples and play
with them yourself and then there's another get
hub repository there that has a bunch of other architectural design patterns that you should can follow both of
...creative from the cat team and there's documentation you're actually pull this up in the browser.
Just to give you an idea of what's here.
And, then I want to leave you with one last free.
...freebie for everybody in the room.
Which is how many here people here working in a real project right now...like some architecture guidance?
Okay, I'll give you a each everybody in hear something free in a second
here's that page so this is the page with this project that has all these examples on
it with documentation about what each of them do
now here's the free thing that I'm giving you all the cat teams here...
Here's where they are they've got a cat clinic that's the map where you can go find them
they're here during conference hours every day here through the...the week you can go down
there take them your architecture tell them what problems...you have
or what guidance you want and they'll spit sit down understand your project and give you that
guidance all completely for free so...you to take advantage that?
And, have a great rest of the...conference and all of the see you next year...